Darryl Dixon

Newport News, Virginia http://PieceDigital.github.io http://github.com/PieceDigital PieceDigitalStudios@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a self-educated web developer with a passion for building websites and web applications with great user experience. I specialize in improving user experience by improving user interfaces and optimising code, which results in greater user retention.

Skills

- Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/Node
- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks: jQuery, ReactJS, AngularJS(basic), ExpressJS, Socket.io
- Tools: Photoshop, Git (and GitHub), Gulp Handlebars.js, Sass
- Others: Responsive Design, Mentoring

Experience

Web Application Developer

Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

Guide Magazine

- Created a fully featured JavaScript chat application, complete with admin panel: http://piecedigital.github.io/gcc-chat
- Designed the app to be touchscreen-friendly and responsive across desktop and mobile
- Constructed server code to be modular and efficient

Freelance Web Developer/Consultant

Mar 2015 - May 2015

MTM Landscaping

- Assisted in design decisions
- Constructed web code for optimal load times

Web Designer/Developer

Oct 2014 - May 2015

Meraki Natural Hair

- Designed the website to be aesthetically comfortable and pleasing, using wireframes and mockup as guides for implementation
- Constructed web code to be manageable and efficient

Education

Free Code Camp Oct 2014 - Apr 2015

• Completed this online curriculum in 6 months, where I learned my skills in full-stack web development. http://FreeCodeCamp.com/

CodeCademy Oct 2014 - Apr 2015

• A general online course where I learned the essentials of web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)